# GRACE ANULIKA EZE

#### **SKILLS**

Programming and Version Control

Python · Pandas · Numpy · Scikit-Learn ·

Pytorch · Git · Github · Kanban

Data and Database Management

SQL · PostgreSQL · SQLAlchemy ·

Data Pipelines · ETL ·

Apache NiFi (beginner) ·

PySpark (beginner)

Visualization

Matplotlib · Seaborn · Plotly · PowerBl

Orchestration and Containerization

Apache Airflow (beginner) .

Docker (beginner)

#### Data

Research · Hypothesis Testing ·

Data Wrangling · Statistical Analysis ·

Analytical Modelling .

Object Serialization

## **EDUCATION**

M.Sc. Mathematical Engineering & M.Sc. Applied Mathematics (EMJMD)

University of L'Aquila, Italy & Ivan Franko National Unive rsity of Lviv, Ukraine.

09/2017 - 07/2019

M.Sc. Mathematical Sciences and Scientific Computing

African Institute of Mathematical Sciences, Cameroon.

08/2016 - 07/2017

**B.Sc. Industrial Mathematics** 

Covenant University, Ogun, Nigeria. 09/2012 - 06/2016

#### **LANGUAGES**

English Native •••••

## German Beginner •••••

## Data Analytics Engineer

\$\ +49 (0) 162 7096 430 @ grace.anulikaeze@gmail.com
\$\tilde{O}\$ https://ghraciella.github.io/ \$\ \Phi\$ Bremen, Germany

## **SUMMARY**

Passionate <u>Data Practitioner</u> with about 4 years of experience in research, developing datadriven solutions and also a well established industrial mathematical background. I am constantly motivated by every new experience I learn through data and its impact on efficient decision making. I have experience in both independent and collaborative workflows for various projects as well as interest in the areas of; data analysis, analytical engineering, data engineering, data science and software development.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Data Practitioner

03/2023 - 09/2023 Remote/Hamburg, DE

#### Neuefische GmbH

Developed a mood based music recommendation system that fine-tunes and makes
personalised music suggestions by introducing user input options with a focus on mood
and genre of the audio tracks.

- Engineered the mood feature of Spotify audio tracks metadata based on modified models of affect and existing research.
- Utilisation of relevant tools for data management, analysis and model development.
- · Identification of business requirements and useful KPIs for various data projects.
- Independent and collaborative development of various machine learning models and data solutions.
- · Open source contribution to Pandas as part of the PyLadies Hamburg community.
- 520 hours of programming practice with team-based development of a project as journeyman's piece.
- <u>Capstone Project: MOOSIC mood based music recommendation system.</u>

#### Research Scientist

08/2019 - 02/2023

## University of Bremen (O2C/ZETEM)

Bremen, DE

- Conducted research on computer vision technologies as well as relevant emerging global best practices for efficient decision making and to foster innovation in project.
- Implemented image processing neural networks for road object segmentation and distance estimation of required road objects which were trained on large multidimensional data files using relevant technologies.
- Collection of test data, camera filter creation, and testing of models on an autonomous research car in alignment with the requirements of the image processing and creative teams.
- Conducted research on optimisation methodologies with a focus on integrating deep learning algorithms into a multi-objective multi-task model.
- Prepared internal presentations, moderated and took part in various topic-based work group discussions.
- Engaged in various professional development activities, including attending training workshops in the data scientist track, seminars, and working on self-development projects to extract insights from different datasets.

### Research and Development Intern

02/2019 - 04/2019

## Abto Software

L'viv, Ukraine

- Generated a comprehensive survey report which reviewed the existing handwritten text recognition techniques, libraries and software solutions. It was then used to foster efficient decision making for the next steps in our project.
- Implemented and presented a simple neural network for character recognition which was trained on the MNIST and E-MNIST dataset.
- Communicated with the team and coordination of tasks using specified project management tools.

## PROJECT AND CERTIFICATION

## Certifications

## **Projects**

<u>GitHub: Skill Aquisition Certificates and Trainings</u>

<u>GitHub : Data Practitioner Project</u> <u>Portfolio</u>